<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Health Writings Blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[healthwritings.com: A blog with practical ideas for improving your health!]]></description><link>http://healthwritings.com/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 21:03:00 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Heart Monitor Reviews]]></title><description><![CDATA[Fitbit Charge 2 The Fitbit Charge 2 can be used to track your daily amount of steps taken, distance traveled, calories burned, floors…]]></description><link>http://healthwritings.com//heart-monitors/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://healthwritings.com//heart-monitors/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;Fitbit Charge 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Fitbit Charge 2 can be used to track your daily amount of steps taken, distance traveled, calories burned, floors climbed, sleep patterns and minutes of activity. Most importantly, it records your Continuous Heart Rate directly from your wrist instead of just using the pulse rate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://support.polar.com/us-en/support/difference-between-heart-rate-and-pulse&quot;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to see an article on the difference between pulse and heart rate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tracking Continuous Heart Rate can help people with diminished heart function avoid triggers such as high heat. The data can be studied to determine what your triggers are. These triggers can increase a person’s heart rate to dangerous levels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The heart rate data can also help to determine when overexertion is reached during exercise. The Fitbit mobile app for iPhone shows you your Resting Heart Rate. It provides the user with information on which heart rate zones have occured during the day. The catagories include Fat Burn, Cardio and Peak. It is best to avoid the Cario and Peak zones if you have a weak heart.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Resting Heart Rate data generates graphs that show the change over time. You can view the changes over a daily, monthly or even yearly time frame. This helps track the progress of your fitness and dietary routines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the device shows that you have a high heart rate, you can use it as an early warning signal to make an appointment with a cardialogist or go to an emergency room. Taking action at the right time can save your life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Fitbit device is also very useful for monitoring your prescription drug use. You can see the effect that a drug is having on your heart rate. This monitoring is available 24/7. If a drug seems to be creating problems, you can ask a doctor whether your dosage needs to  be adjusted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can buy a Fitbit Charge 3 for $150 at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fitbit.com/shop/charge3&quot;&gt;Fitbit.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;KardiaMobile EKG Monitor by AliveCor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The KardiaMobile is an EKG monitor that can be used at home. The Kardia app can be installed on your iPhone. It captures data on heart rate, heart rhythm and symptoms. This can allow for the early detection of Atrial Fibrillation or other forms of Cardiac Arrhythmia. It can show if your heart rhythm is normal or not.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you have Arrhythmia it will show you how well your medication is working and when you need to go to see a doctor or even to the emergency room.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Kardia device actually gives you information on your heart rate, instead of your pulse rate like the Fitbit. If you have Arrhythmia your heart rate will be faster than your puplse rate. The difference between the two will diminish as the amount Arrhythmia decreases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Omron 7 Series Upper Arm Blood Pressure Monitor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Omron 7 Series is an automatic wrist-based blood pressure monitor. I can help you find out what your blood pressure and heart rate is at any given time. You can even use it while you are lying down. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This device show Cardiac Arrythmia very accurately. There is an app for it which could be installed on your iPhone to track both your blood pressure and your heart rate. You can see how the numbers shift over a long periods of time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Both the Omron and Kardia show you your heart rate. These are very important statistics when used together with the puplse rate from the Fitbit. Together the numbers can be used as an early warning signal for Cardiac Arrythmia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://healthwritings.com/disclaimer/&quot;&gt;Medical Disclaimer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Heart Health]]></title><description><![CDATA[Losing Weight Limit your amount of bread you eat each day. Don’t eat anything after 5 PM. Water retention could contribute to weight gain…]]></description><link>http://healthwritings.com//heart-health/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://healthwritings.com//heart-health/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 22:15:45 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;Losing Weight&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limit your amount of bread you eat each day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t eat anything after 5 PM.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Water retention could contribute to weight gain. Diuretics can help with this problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look up your Body Mass Index (BMI) to find out what your optimal weight is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Exercise&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Yellow Emperor is the mythological founder of Ancient China. He is credited with many inventions including the founding of cardiology. According to Chinese tradition, a person was considered healthy in they could walk 10 minutes at a speed of 6 kilometers per hour (or 3.73 miles per hour).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your doctors can send you to a stress test to check your heart function. The test can estimate you can estimate your highest capacity speed. During the test, you move with a speed that is 90% of your capacity. The speed will change depending upon your capacity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://healthwritings.com/disclaimer/&quot;&gt;Medical Disclaimer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Medical Disclaimer]]></title><description><![CDATA[HealthWritings.com does not give medical advice. HealthWritings.com contains articles on medical topics; however, no warranty is made that…]]></description><link>http://healthwritings.com//disclaimer/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://healthwritings.com//disclaimer/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 22:15:45 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;HealthWritings.com does not give medical advice.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HealthWritings.com contains articles on medical topics; however, no warranty is made that any of the articles are accurate. There is absolutely no assurance that any statement contained or cited in an article touching on medical matters is true, correct, precise, or up-to-date. Even if a statement made about medicine is accurate, it may not apply to you or your symptoms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The medical information provided on HealthWritings.com is, at best, of a general nature and cannot substitute for the advice of a medical professional (for instance, a qualified doctor/physician, nurse, pharmacist/chemist, and so on). HealthWritings.com is not a doctor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;None of the individual contributors, system operators, developers, sponsors of HealthWritings.com nor anyone else connected to HealthWritings.com can take any responsibility for the results or consequences of any attempt to use or adopt any of the information presented on this web site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nothing on HealthWritings.com or included as part of any project of Web Express, Inc., should be construed as an attempt to offer or render a medical opinion or otherwise engage in the practice of medicine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>